# **JACOB SWARTZ**

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

515 Central Ave, Unit T, Mountain View, CA 94043 (415) 766-1867 jacob.sf.us@gmail.com https://linkedin.com/in/jacobswartz

Eager and experienced full stack developer with a frontend focus. Specialized experience with ecommerce solutions and SEO & SEM. Intuition for detail and visual aesthetics. Highly self-motivated—capable of working independently as well as being a key asset to any team, with a passion to share knowledge and improve & expand skill sets.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

#### Development

- ES6 JavaScript/TypeScript
  PHPUnit/xdebug
- Object-oriented PHP
- Node.js/ Webpack
- Vue.js/Angular
- HTML5/CSS3/Sass
- MvSQL
- Bash
- SVN/git
- SEO/SEM

#### Testing

- Jasmine/Karma
- JMeter/Apache Bench
- KCachegrind
- New Relic/PageSpeed/Blackfire
  Yammer

# Collaboration

- IRC
- Basecamp
- JIRA/Trac
  - Slack

#### Virtualization

- VirtualBox/VMWare
- Vagrant/PuPHPet
- Amazon Web Services
- Docker

#### 0S

- Debian Linux
  - MacOS
  - · Windows 7, 10

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Freelance Consultant

#### The Internet; Jan 2015 - Present

- Develop and maintain websites and custom features for clients
- · Utilize APIs to import product data from multiple vendors
- Generate tailored reports from cart platforms for ecommerce clients
- · Create email campaigns using MailChimp and Campaign Monitor
- Install and maintain FTP, mail, and web servers

#### **Creative Technologist at Bluestone Creative**

## Cincinnati, Ohio; Mar 2014 - Sep 2014

- Created websites using HTML5, PHP, JavaScript, Sass, and Foundation
- Managed hardware and software for in-house web, storage, and FTP servers
- · Set up tools for project tracking, task management, and time logging

#### Software Engineer at Ask.com

#### Oakland, California; Oct 2012 - Jul 2013

- Front and backend development on an agile development team responsible for over 20 domain-specific search engine results pages
- Repaired revenue-generating sites penalized by Google's search algorithm "Panda"
- · Made Questions & Answers site mobile-friendly by implementing a responsive grid
- · Assisted designers and creative directors in authoring a unified website style guide



#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

515 Central Ave, Unit T, Mountain View, CA 94043 (415) 766-1867 jacob.sf.us@gmail.com https://linkedin.com/in/jacobswartz

# **EXPERIENCE** CONT'D

# Web Developer at FontShop International, Inc

San Francisco, California; Oct 2008 – July 2012

- Created a responsive ecommerce experience using HTML5, CSS3 + Sass, and JavaScript
- Developed font rendering tool for sampling over 100,000 typefaces using php-gd
- Implemented sitewide templating and internationalization supporting 4 languages
- Created a shopping cart checkout system using CyberSource, Ogone, and PayPal
- Optimized pages resulting in decreased load time and increased SEO ranking
- Replaced image and Flash hack typography solutions with web fonts using Typekit
- Maintained self-hosted WordPress blog extended with custom features
- Helped organize and run TYPO San Francisco-one of Europe's most successful design conferences-for its U.S. premiere at Yerba Buena Center for the Arts

# Web Developer at Fish Flirt Marketing

Dayton, Ohio; May 2007 - Oct 2008

- Developed ecommerce sites with the LAMP stack, W3C-compliant HTML, CSS, and JS
- Installed, configured, and managed SVN, web, and mail servers

**EDUCATION** 

Sinclair Community College

Dayton, Ohio; Apr 2007 - Oct 2008

• AAS, Computer Information Systems

REFERENCES

Available on request